Guide to the Hamilton Basso Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1878-1964; Series II; 6.25' (15 boxes)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - "For P. McG.": typescript, 1961 Jun 16 (Box 19, Folder 345)
    - "The Gates Open": typescript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 346)
    - "Greenwich Village": typescript, [1926?] (Box 19, Folder 347)
    - "Holiday": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 348)
    - "The Ladies of Ladd": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 349-52)
    - "Letters from America": notes, 1959, 1961, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 353)
    - Letter to the New York Times: newspaper clipping, 1955 Apr 12 (Box 19, Folder 354)
    - "Longfellow": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 355)
    - "A Momentary Digression": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 356)
    - "Nocturne": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 357)
    - "Notes for a Journal": typescript, holograph, printed material, 1948-62 (Box 19, Folder 358)
    - Notes on voyage to Samoa and Fiji, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 359)
    - "Pinwheel": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 360)
    - Poems: typescript, corrected, [1926?] (Box 19, Folder 361)
    - Profile of H. T. Webster: newspaper clipping, 1949 Dec 6 (Box 19, Folder 362)
    - "A Prologue": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 363)
    - Puerto Cortez: notes, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 364)
    - "Quimby": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 365)
    - Review of A Certain Measure by Ellen Glasgow: newspaper clipping, 1943 Oct 17 (Box 19, Folder 366)
    - "Spain, 1926": notebook, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 367)
    - "Swans in Their Piety": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 368)
    - "10:30 A.M.": typescript, [1926?] (Box 19, Folder 369)
    - "Thomas Wolfe": holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 19, Folder 370)
    - "Two Little Pigs": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 371)
    - "The USA: Americanism": printed material, 1958, 1961, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 372-73)
    - Untitled fragments, 1926 (Box 19, Folder 374)
    - "We, the Outsider": notecards, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 375)
    - "The Years Change Verdia Crane": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 376)
- Other Papers, 1932-75; Series III; 0.5' (1 box)
  Series III, Other Papers, consists of five alphabetically arranged subseries, with folders within them each arranged alphabetically.
  - CONTRACTS
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1932-41 (Box 20, Folder 377)
    - Curtis Publishing Company, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 378)
    - Doubleday & Co., Inc., 1950-62 (Box 20, Folder 379)
    - Loew's Incorporated, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 380)
    - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, 1936 (Box 20, Folder 381)
    - Twentieth Century Fox, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 382)
  - FINANCIAL DOCUMENTS
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1934, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 383)
    - Doubleday & Co., Inc., 1954-65 (Box 20, Folder 384-85)
    - Hutchinson Publishing Group, 1965-67 (Box 20, Folder 386)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-65 (Box 20, Folder 387)
    - U. S. Information Agency, 1968 Jan 31 (Box 20, Folder 388)
    - Viking Press, 1964-75 (Box 20, Folder 389)
  - MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS
    - Bow and arrow instruction (Box 20, Folder 390)
    - Census: U. S. Negro population, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 391)
    - Notes on airplane engines, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 392)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Motuvini, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 393)
      See also: The Swing of the Compass Background material, Box 11, folders 207-208
    - Spratling, William, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 394)
    - Wolfe, Thomas, n.d.
  - PRINTED MATERIALS
    - Basso, Hamilton: profiles, 1954, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 395)
    - Beauregard, 1933 May 31 (Box 20, Folder 396)
    - Courthouse Square, 1936
    - Days Before Lent, 1939 Jul 31 (Box 20, Folder 397)
    - Double Dealer, 1951 Jan 21
    - Exploration of the Valley of the Amazon, [1951] (Box 20, Folder 398)
    - The Greenroom, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 399)
    - Holiday for Sinners, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 400)
    - The Light Infantry Ball, 1959
    - Maugham, W. Somerset, 1951 Jun (Box 20, Folder 401)
    - Showboats by Philip Graham, 1952
    - A Touch of the Dragon, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 402)
    - The View from Pompey's Head, 1954-55 (Box 20, Folder 403)
    - Wolfe, Thomas, 1946, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 404)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Markle, Fletcher: "The Great Lady": radio play, typescript carbon, corrected, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 405)
    - Sadow, Robert: "Raw material on Thomas Wolfe": typescript, corrected, 1936 Jan 18 (Box 20, Folder 406)
    - Saxon, Robert: Review of Courthouse Square: typescript, 1936 (Box 20, Folder 407)
    - Wallstein, Robert: "The Great Lady" radio play: typescript, mimeograph, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 408)
    - Wolfe, Thomas: "The Child by Tiger": typescript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 409)
- Oversize, 1861-1951; 2.0' (1 box)
  Series IV contains Oversize materials from Series II, Writings.
  - Exploration of the Valley of the Amazon: maps, [1951?] (Box 21, Folder 410)
  - The Light Infantry Ball: notes: printed material, Savannah Daily News, 1861 Jan 21 (Box 21, Folder 411)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.25' (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 22: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, Folder 5 (Box 22, Folder 412)
  - Box 1, Folder 6 (Box 22, Folder 413)
  - Box 1, Folder 7 (Box 22, Folder 414)
  - Box 1, Folder 14 (Box 22, Folder 415)
  - Box 1, Folder 21 (Box 22, Folder 416)
  - Box 1, Folder 22 (Box 22, Folder 417)
  - Box 1, Folder 27 (Box 22, Folder 418)
  - Box 1, Folder 32 (Box 22, Folder 419)
  - Box 2, Folder 46 (Box 22, Folder 420)
  - Box 2, Folder 52 (Box 22, Folder 421)
  - Box 2, Folder 63 (Box 22, Folder 422)
  - Box 3, Folder 80 (Box 22, Folder 423)
  - Box 3, Folder 93 (Box 22, Folder 424)
  - Box 3, Folder 100 (Box 22, Folder 425)
  - Box 3, Folder 103 (Box 22, Folder 426)
  - Box 4, Folder 123 (Box 22, Folder 427)
  - Box 19, Folder 334 (Box 22, Folder 428)
  - Box 19, Folder 335 (Box 22, Folder 429)
  - Box 19, Folder 339 (Box 22, Folder 430)
  - Box 19, Folder 348 (Box 22, Folder 431)
  - Box 19, Folder 355 (Box 22, Folder 432)
  - Box 19, Folder 356 (Box 22, Folder 433)
  - Box 19, Folder 357 (Box 22, Folder 434)
  - Box 19, Folder 361 (Box 22, Folder 435)
  - Box 19, Folder 369 (Box 22, Folder 436)
  - Box 19, Folder 370 (Box 22, Folder 437)
  - Box 19, Folder 374 (Box 22, Folder 438)
  - Box 19, Folder 409 (Box 22, Folder 439)